[Music]
do
and we are live good evening and good
day everybody
uh it's great to see you all welcome to
episode
29 of the ask abijit show
so let me take a look at who all is here
who is with us
it's great to see you all great to see
you all
so as you know today we are doing
history which is i think everyone's
favorite topic so
let's get into the questions
with question number one
okay question number one is from anup
anub asks what is the brahmi script and
what's the difference between the brahmi
script
and the deva nagari script okay first of
all it is not the brahmi script it is
the brahmi script brahmi script
so this is an ancient script that
emerged sometime in the about two and a
half thousand years before today so let
me
show you what it looks like let me share
my screen here
okay okay let's take a look at this
so this is the brahmi script of barami
alphabet
yeah it emerged somewhere in 500 bce
approximately
so this is what it looks like it's an
ancient script
as you can see these are the consonants
in the script
they go just as any as the devnet
so this script even though it's an
ancient script can be used
to write any modern indian language
so it's just one of the many scripts
that emerged in
india over the ages the brahmani script
the karoshi script
before that you have the undeciphered
indus valley or saraswati
civilization script which has still not
been undecided
still not been deciphered and then you
have many modern scripts that we
are that are in use today so many of the
scripts that
are in use today are descended from
brahmi
so this is one of the old scripts
ancient scripts of india and
how is it different from dev nagari well
this is the devanagari script if you can
see this here
so this this script
emerged during the 8th century about
1200 years ago
it is descend it descended from the
ancient gupta script called nagari
and this is the script that is used to
write various indian languages such as
hindi
marathi etc so this is a modern script
this is still in news right now
so that is the difference between brahmi
and devanagari devnari is
the modern script that's used to write
sanskrit hindi etc
brahmi was also used to write sanskrit
and various prakrit languages etc about
two and a half thousand years ago
beginning around two and a half thousand
years ago
so that is in very short
the difference between
between brahmi and devanagari
okay let's go to question number two
okay the modern science of linguistics
says that the north indian languages are
members of the indo-european
language family that included persian
russian spanish english etc
while southern indian languages such as
tamil are
not members of the india indo-european
language family
do you accept this does this mean that
tamils are not indian or aryan
and that dravidian is a real thing okay
good question
so first of all you
you have uh stated that the modern
science of linguistics
well i disagree with this very premise
premise that
linguistics is a science linguistics my
friends is
not a scientific discipline and why is
that so
first of all it lacks a clearly defined
set of rules or laws
secondly it is unfalsifiable a
scientific theory or a scientific
discipline has to be falsifiable
if you have a linguistic theory it has
to be falsifiable if it is to be
considered to be science so linguistics
is not falsifiable it's unfalsifiable
thirdly whatever laws exist in
linguistics
these laws are highly malleable they
depend on consensus
and when you have something like
consensus between experts it means that
you have politics and coalition building
so so that's why it's not a science
linguistics can be considered to be a
science
only when it deals with a logical
rules-based language such as panini and
sanskrit
so that's the only language that is 100
logical
context free and rules based so
linguistics can be considered to be
scientific only when you look at panini
sanskrit
right and the fact that linguistics
lacks a well accepted and clearly
defined set
set of rules or laws unlike physics for
instance
this makes linguistics prone to being
misused
to prove an incorrect hypothesis
so i hope that clarifies the fact that
linguistics
is not a science okay linguistics is all
about coalitions and consensus and all
that nonsense
which means if you have a group of
experts who are considered group of
individuals
who have been given the title of eminent
linguists or or experts
then they can get together and they can
put forth any theory they like
and then it becomes the accepted
consensus that's not how science works
right and yes so
uh northern indian languages sanskrit
etc are members of the
indo-european language family now that
now clearly there is
a connection between all these languages
and the oldest known languages
language of this family is vedic
sanskrit
right and like you said persians spanish
russian
french english latin etc are members of
this family of this language family
now southern indian languages like tamil
are classified in a different language
family called
called the dravidian language family in
linguistics
right now it is well known that
uh genetically there is no difference
between the people of northern southern
east and western india but there clearly
is a disparity in the languages yes
so i don't know how how closely tamil is
related to telugu for instance or
kannada for instance i think telugu has
at least
at least 40 percent sanskrit vocabulary
but yes the uh linguistic uh grammar and
all that may be different yeah
so this this doesn't mean that tamil or
kannada or telugu etc
are not indian by the way yeah
and we don't even have a definition of
what is aryan
so the northern indian languages are
classified as indo-aryan languages part
of the larger indo-european group
so these are all arbitrary
classifications what needs to be
what's happened is that this is all
a consequence of the theories that were
developed
by people like max miller and other
later linguists
in the 19th and 20th centuries so these
theories are all developed by white men
by europeans these are eurocentric
theories
there is no linguistic
research being done in india there are
no linguistics experts in india name
one i mean people will say this that ira
within mahadeva needs some great
linguistic expert
and he deciphered the so-called harappan
the the he supposedly deciphered the
harappan script that is nonsense i have
gone through his papers
it is complete nonsense his so-called
decipherment of the
harappan script so he was no linguistics
expert by the way
he is he has this great reputation and
he's like worshiped as a god
ira within mahadevan but well clearly
his
analysis and his claims don't stand up
to scrutiny
so the fact is what needs to happen is
that we need to start
researching linguistics especially the
indian languages
from an indian's perspective with and it
should be done by it should be driven by
indian experts that's what needs to
happen
so far everything that we learn about
indian history and indian linguistics
is learned from the research
that europeans have done or westerners
have done and the conclusions they have
drawn
and they have come up with these
language families and all that so we
need to
i would say we need to do this research
a priori from
from scratch and construct our own
language families based upon the logic
that we have inherited from thousands of
years from our ancestors
the linguistic logic because the birth
of linguistics as a discipline
as a science starts with
panini panini himself did cite a number
of
older linguists who came before his time
and whose work
whose works are now lost but he has
cited those works so the science of
linguistics was there in india
and when it was being done in india it
was actually a science it was all
algorithmic and logical
today these europeans have messed it up
there's no logic to it
so we need to rediscover our indigenous
science of linguistics
and then we need to apply it to our
languages
unfortunately there is no institute of
linguistics in india
there's no research being done so these
are the things that i i speak about
often because these are very uh glaring
facts
so i uh disagree that tamils are not
indian
or tamils are not aryan and that
dravidian is a real thing this is all
nonsense these are foreign
categories these are categories that
foreigners have imposed upon us
i do not accept
i do not recognize any of these foreign
categories we need to come up with our
own
categories with our own understanding of
who
of who we are that's what needs to
happen okay
so first of all there is no such thing
as an aryan ethnicity or aryan culture
or aryan
language group or any such thing all
indians are the same
all right even tamil even even the
people of southern india are aryans
if if there is such a thing as an aryan
ethnicity
it is the people of the indian
subcontinent and the people of iran
that is the only acceptable aryan
ethnicity
europeans are not aryans i mean some
people have asked me in the past that i
spoke about the indo-greeks
then some indians have some greek blood
does it mean that we are aryans
so the assumption is that the greeks are
aryans so the assumption is that the
lighter skinned people or white-skinned
people are aryans
and darker-skinned people are not aryans
that is nonsense these are the
misconceptions that our education system
has
poured into our heads the only
ethnicity that can be considered to be
an aryan if aryan is an ethnicity
is the indo-iranian people the people of
the entirety of the indian subcontinent
and the iranians so i hope that answers
this question it's
yeah right so let's go to the next
question
this is by mayank europeans initially
colonized the world for spices
then why is it that most of their food
is still bland
yeah that's a great question i mean you
should try
dutch food i mean if any dutch person is
listening to me i'm i'm sorry i mean
very nice people but try their food it's
terrible
i mean it looks great the moment you
taste it it's all sour everything is
sour i don't know why it is that way
so yes you're right european food is
extremely bland
i mean take a look at the food that you
find in the british isles
my goodness the only only condiments
they use are salt and pepper that's it
and just a little
bit of pepper and that's it that's it
it's all spiced
so the truth is that the europeans did
not colonize the world for spices
they colonized the world for plunder
what happened was that when the ottomans
cut off india's access to europe and
vice versa
they also cut off europe's access to
india so when they conquered
the present-day region of turkey which
is mostly anatolia and
the western part is trace ancient trace
so that that essentially cut off the
land route between india
and the western part of eurasia which is
now called europe
and therefore the ancients uh trade in
spices that had been going
on for for many centuries
since the roman times that abruptly came
to an
end right with the fall of the
of the byzantine empire and that's why
they started
i mean they craved these spices i think
roman food was better so
better tasting than present-day european
food in many places
the romans did use lots of indian spices
so i think
that's that was that so the cutting off
of the trade route
gave the initial impetus to the
europeans to discover a different
different uh way of reaching india
by sea and that's what gave rise to
these journeys by
columbus and vasco de gama they which
which were clearly
uh these journeys these quests to
rediscover india
did not we're not for the sake of spices
there were there were these papal bulls
okay the pope had
issued what's called these bulls or
directives
to these uh to these uh
voyagers and they were directed
they were told that the pope gave them
the authority
to claim any non-christian land
for the crown whatever crown they served
so christopher columbus
set out to conquer india
on behalf of the spanish crown their
intention was to colonize and destroy
india
and vascular government did the same
thing on behalf of the portuguese and
his
behavior once he reached india is very
indicative of his
hostile aggressive and malified intent
if you if you see the his actions
vasquez actions
once he reached the coast of india i
mean he burned a ship full of men and
women and children
yeah he stole all the valuables and then
burned the ship
burned these people alive he uh used
cannons against indian cities
cannons on his ships etc so these were
from the very beginning uh
expeditions that had a very malified
intent they expected the
intent was to conquer and colonize so
the colonization was not for the sake of
spices the spices was just the initial
impetus
the the real uh reason for the
colonization was to plunder
the lands mainly india later also africa
the east indies etc
and to some extent some parts of china
so that is what happened so the food i
mean your food habits don't really
change
so that's why the food is still bland
european food we know it's it's quite
bland
try german food try dutch food try try
british food
i think the french and the the in the
italians have better tastes
but overall it's quite bland even the
greeks have better taste
so mediterranean food is nicer it's
tastier
but overall european fluid would like
you said is bland
okay which is the original language
prakrit
or sanskrit well first of all there is
no such language as prakrit
the prakrits are a group of languages
these are upper branch languages
these are corruptions of sanskrit
the oldest known language in the world
is vedic sanskrit then you had
classical sanskrit from the time of
panini panini
is believed to have lived around 500 bce
approximately we don't really know if
that is correct
maybe he lived much he lived much before
that we don't really know
the accepted consensus among experts
among eminent historians
is that panini lived somewhere around
300 or 500 bce
right so that is considered to be the
era of classical sanskrit or panini and
sanskrit
the prakrits came after that the
prakrits were a group of languages
that eventually gave birth to the
languages that are spoken
in northern western etc india today
so the prakrits are upper branch
languages these are corruptions of the
classical sanskrit these are basically
degradations of sanskrit
these are various degraded and corrupted
dialects
of sanskrit gandhari the ancient
gandhari language
that was spoken across central asia
that is an example of a prakrita
language and then
even pali could be i think pali is
considered to be a pre prakrit language
perhaps it was the langu it was
definitely a corruption of the sanskrit
language it is
it's the language that was spoken in
among the common people
during the mauryan times during the time
of the buddha
especially the buddha yeah the buddha's
time so the buddha is
believed to have lived around 500 bce
approximately in that
in that time frame if the experts are
correct i'm not really sure if that is
true but yeah okay
so the buddha did preach in sanskr in
pali instead of sanskrit because he
wanted to reach the common
man and woman so
to summarize to answer your question in
brief
sanskrit is the oldest known language in
the entire world
i mean vedic sanskrit the prakrits are
descended descendants these are
corruptions
of sanskrit these are various corrupted
dialects of sanskrit and they gave rise
to the
modern indian languages the northern and
western indian languages those that are
classified under the indo-aryan
language family and the indo-iranian
language family as well
okay this is by andrew some
anthropologists claim that
horses do not exist in the fossil record
of the indian subcontinent before the
so-called aryan invasion can you address
this
obviously horses were an essential part
of the chariot warfare described in
sanskrit texts
why do they make this claim and how to
refute it this is an excellent question
sir
so yes they do make this this claim
that uh there were no horses in india
and that's why
it is the foreign audience who brought
the horses from central asia
they brought the horses and chariots
into india during the invasion
and that's why you have this reference
to horses etc
but they claim that before during the
harappan times etc there were no horses
the horses only came with the aryan
invaders of india
so that is the claim so let me refute
this claim it's a very good question
let me share
an image
okay if you can see this so this is an
excerpt from
now you can see it this is an expert
from a from a book called
the history of ancient india portraits
of a nation by
kapoor by kamlesh kapoor so it describes
clearly that there is
the about the early evidence of horses
in the ganga and the
siddhava horses are described in the
vedas we know that
rigveda verse whatever describes that
the horse is having 34 ribs
17 sets of ribs and this is also true
for the arabian horse the arabian horse
also has 17 sets of ribs
and the arabian horses is known to have
existed at least 10 000 years before
today at least
okay now the central asian horse has 36
ribs which means 18
sets of ribs now in india fossil remains
of the shivalik horse
provides us with the archaeological
proof of the fact that the vedic horse
is a native
indian breed it has 17 sets of ribs
34 ribs in total okay and
there is clear evidence of the horse
bones etcetera
in various sindhu or or harappan
archaeological sites such as lothal
kalibangan suruku
in india as well as in mohenjo-daro in
pakistan
and horse remains both domestic and the
wild
variety have been found at places such
as
mahagara in the interior of india dating
to before 6500 bce
so there is clear evidence that
horses existed in india way before the
so-called aryan invasion
and is as early as 1924 sir john
marshall
the then director general of the asi
recorded the presence of the smaller
variety of horse at the site of the
excavation
at mohenjo-daro so it the book this
concludes that it's surprising that this
80 year old record
is missing from all the books on the
subject of the homeland of the vedic
indians right
so here's a different image this is
the upper image here if you can see my
mouse pointer is a horse figurine
from lothal which is in present day
saurashtra
or kach western india which is a
harappan era site archaeological site
and here you have an ancient
chess set from the same region
chess was invented in india during the
harappan or preharapanira
so this is an ancient chess set with a
horse
as you can see this is a horse it's a
horse chest piece so once again you have
evidence of the horse in india
this is that figure in in more detail
and now we have this inconvenient fact
this is the bimbecta caves rock shelter
in
central india this the this dates back
from the upper paleolithic era
which starts around 50 000 bce
up to around 10 000 bce now human
habitation has been known in this place
for
at least 100 000 years and as you can
see
this ancient rock art in india depicts
horse riders it's very clear i mean it's
unmistakable
these are horse riders here is another
one
this seems to be a a scene that depicts
a battle of some kind
people riding horses and holding
javelins or spears
and here once again you have
what's clearly a stallion or stallions
and these are ancient very ancient
paintings
right so this is unmistakable
irrefutable evidence
of the presence of horses in india
thousands and thousands of years before
today and we have the evidence
from the harappan uh region
the in the harappan sites such as lothal
mohenjo-daro and even pre-harappan sites
which means before
this region became a proper civilization
and urban civilization
before that it was rural and it was like
less developed
there is a so-called pre-harappan phase
that's around 8 000
years before today so even in that time
you find horse remains
so it is incredible it's it's very
surprising
that you have this sort of uh
misinformation
that has been being spread in the name
of scholarship
that there were no horses in india
before the
so-called aryan invasion which is
supposed to have happened
three and a half thousand years before
today now once again according to their
own
logic if there was an rn invasion three
and a half thousand years ago
which came in from central asia then why
don't we have
horses with 36 ribs in india
why do we only have evidence of
archaeology i mean
fossils of horses with 34 ribs in india
so it this is this makes it very clear
that this so-called
academic and scholarly claim by all
these eminent historians
is a complete outright lie and
fabrication
and this essentially puts to rest the
entire horse argument
in favor of the so-called aryan invasion
theory
okay this is by dhiraj did
nehru help china to conquer tibet
by providing food supplies such as rice
well once again we have to deal with the
great
shriner so let me share
an image share a website that i have
because you should not take my word for
this you should see it for yourself
okay so this is an article that
references
a book by claude nehru's
india helped china conquer tibet so
let's let's read this
let's read this together
so the chinese invasion of tibet which
culminated in the 1962 war between india
and china has often been portrayed as
the great chinese betrayal a stab in the
back
as jawaharlal nehru would say with much
pain and anguish
klodaki in his 2017 book tibet the last
months of a free nation
provided proved with fresh shreds of
evidence that the notion of betrayal was
a farce
it was a stab from the front as mj akbar
observed in his biography on nehru
four the then prime minister sri naroji
and his comrades refused to see the
writing on the wall for more than a
decade in his latest book will tibbett
ever find her soul again
rp comes up with another explosive
revelation
that nahiru's india supplied rise to the
invading pla troops in tibet
when they were busy rampaging and
decimating the tibetan way of life and
culture
in the early 1950s the most grotesque
incident of this period was the feeding
of the place troops
with rice coming through india writes
the france-based
france-born expert on tibetan china
without delhi's active support the
chinese troops would not have been able
to survive in tibet
tibet before the massive chinese influx
of the 1950s was a self-sufficient
society
etc they only ate
barley roast barley known as champa
which had been their staple food for
centuries
the influx of fresh troops brought the
first serious problem in the new
coexistence between the chinese
occupants in the lhasa government the
availability of food stuff
to overcome the food crisis in tibet
chairman mao
and his comrades look towards india
s k krishna krishna
the indian trade agent ita in yantze
mentioned that the chinese government
had requested the government of india
for an agreement
allowing facilities for the transport of
food and other supplies through india
the chinese government wanted transit
facilities for 10 000 tons of food
grains through india
as a special case mr nehru first agreed
after careful consideration
to allow the transit of around 3000 tons
of rice to tibet
while pointing out the transport
problems the government of india
expressed their willingness to consider
it together with all
outstanding issues etc and sadly
but not surprisingly the tibetan part of
the story was soon forgotten
blinded by dark ideological lenses or
even duped
by china's by by chimera india refused
to see the true nature of communist
china and its devastating present
presence in tibet it did not even grasp
that china was hitting out at india
when it gave a call in the 17-point
agreement to drive out
imperialistic forces from tibet because
india had a diplomatic and even a
military
presence in tibet india had
troops in tibet before the chinese
invasion and even during the chinese
invasion
india also had a diplomatic presence and
various other government officials
so so basically the chinese
called for driving out aggressive
imperialistic forces from tibet which
they meant by
by which they meant india this rise
diplomacy
continued for well over four years in
1954 it was reemphasized that india
would continue to supply rice
with the people's liberation army
stationed in tibet
rice with china would buy was intended
exclusively for tibet etc
and then at the end of 1954 they did not
need indian rice anymore
so this is the truth this is not
my opinion and this is not the only
article this is just one article that
illustrates the fact
of what happened so basically the
chinese
soldiers who invaded tibet would never
have been
able to survive in tibet let alone
occupy
it had shri jawaharlal
nehru not fed them with indian rice
at the time india was a poor country
india had famines and all that because
of the depredations of the british
and yet india was busy feeding its rice
to the invading chinese soldiers in
tibet
so so mr nehru the great statesman
shrinaruji
aided and abetted the chinese invasion
of tibet
without mr nehru china would never have
been able to occupy and conquer tibet
these are hard facts i am not making it
up i just showed you the article
so yes it is true mr nero did
facilitate china's conquest of tibet by
providing
critical food supplies rice to the
chinese
ishan asks what are your thoughts on the
non-aligned movement and india's
post-independence
post-world war ii foreign policy of
non-alignment
as a whole it was what is what is my
thought
what are my thoughts it was detrimental
to india's interests
it harmed india immensely the
non-aligned movement was an exercise in
mediocrity
it was an exercise in not pursuing your
national interests
mr nehru believed that he was a great
world leader a great statesman
and he wanted to propose an alternate
native form of
of geopolitics in which small
insignificant countries get together
and say that we are not aligned with
either the us usa or the ussr
but this was all hypocrisy because mr
nehru
basically turned india into a soviet
satellite state
india was a soviet ally during the cold
war it's well known
i mean nobody can deny that fact so
india on the one on the one hand said
that it was non-aligned it was part of
the non-aligned movement
on the other hand it was a soviet
satellite state so it was complete
hypocrisy
it harmed india immensely india would
have benefited greatly if it had pursued
its own national interest in a
hard-nosed fashion
so this was this was one of the most
terrible foreign policy blunders in
india's modern history
it basically set the tone to what india
has become today a soft
punching bag kind of state which can't
influence affairs even in its
immediate neighborhood
ganesh asks i have always wondered what
was the actual size of the ancient
cities described in the mahabharata in
ramayana
what were they like compared to current
cities and what was the politics like
as we hear about janapadas and such
in ramayana what's my insight
so see if you look at the ancient
uh if you look at ancient india if you
look at the
the uh peak of the harappan
era of india's civilization then it was
a vast extensive highly developed highly
urbanized
completely industrialized enormous
geographical region
which was greater than mesopotamia in
the middle east
and and egypt put together that's how
big it was
it was completely industrialized it was
completely urbanized
right and you had big cities and the
total population of this region
at that time was around 5 million people
so the population was
minuscule compared to what india's
population is today
and therefore the cities too correspond
were correspondingly smaller if you look
at the
uh extent of the cities of harappa and
mohenjo-daro
they are not really very big but they
are very well developed
and they are very they are perfectly
completely
urbanized and the largest site that we
have is uh
is rakiguri which again is not that
large
so the population of the biggest cities
would have been in
maybe tens of thousands perhaps which is
like
nothing compared to today's size right
but for those days it was great it was
like it was
it was a great it was very much for for
that time
considering the total population was
around 5 million
so the city the scale and size of the
cities
was different it was much smaller than
what it is today because
the population was much less
so that is the kind of size of the
ancient cities that you asked about
what was the uh politics like
so ancient india as you as we know it
had uh
these these mahajanapadas
are a more recent phenomenon but what
the kind of
governance system you had during the
harappan phase of our civilization
it's not very well known if you look at
the uh
archaeological remains of these cities
you find that there are no
royal palaces and the most extensive
architecture is reserved for public
facilities like the public bath or the
assembly hall or whatever right
so there are no royal palaces there is
no sign
of any aristocracy or royalty so it
looks like you had that sort of
democracy
ghana tantra even during the harappan
era of our civilization
and during the mahajanapada era we
clearly know that these
we had ganatantra which is democracy so
it was
a democracy with a king at the top so
basically you would have
an assembly of people who would elect
the king the king was not hereditary
right
the the uh the title of king was not
hereditary
often it would be passed on from father
to son but through elections
so you had that sort of uh democracy in
ancient india
it was democracy with indian
characteristics even the greeks
have written about the fact that india
was a democratic civilization you had
democracy in india
and this democracy dates far back far
before the greek
era i mean before the before greece even
existed
as a nation or civilization so india
essentially is the birthplace of
democracy and
so that is the kind of politics we have
we had in india
in that era
they just asks who are the lecturers
described in the mahabharat they are
even described in the mahabharat war as
well are the greeks or egyptians
where what were these outside
civilizations these were not
civilizations
so the uh best
rough translation for the word lecture
into english
is barbarian so barbarian is a greek and
roman term
the greeks called people barbarians who
were not
so anyone who was not greek was a
barbarian according to the greeks
now according to this sanskrit term
litcha mlecha was
any people any kingdom
or race of people who were non-vedic
who did not follow the vedic traditions
so this could also include as you know
as i have spoken before
lots of indian kingdoms were established
in central asia
north and west of the himalayas there
were many waves of migrations
outside of india as is very well known
even in the archaeological record
the mithani the hittites etc the casites
so we know that indians did go north and
west
out of india and they formed many
kingdoms
uh in these regions uttarakuru
madra etc north and west of india so
after some time eventually over time
they stopped practicing vedic traditions
in their entirety so they basically
became
degraded vedic people their their
culture became degraded and these are
the people that
were called lechas because they had
stopped
performing the vedic rituals and
traditions the way they were supposed to
be
performed so that is one definition of
nature which means these are
descendants of indians but who have
become kind of
non-indianized to some extent the other
definition of lectures are completely
non-indian
tribes or whatever you know so for
example the greeks
can be considered to be a non-indian
tribe they are the descendants of the
rig vedic
alina clan but over the millennia they
became very much non-indian
so the greeks welcome were called
matches and
various other other tribes and
ethnicities were also called
lectures so the best definition is those
who don't
follow the vedic way of life that is
lecture
so it is the best equivalent word in
english is
barbarian someone who is not cultured
and not civilized
that's what it means
harshawardhan asks why are there
mentions of discrimination in the
mahabharata era such as
ekklaviya karna etc did these scenarios
really take place were they not allowed
to gain education and teachings
well i don't know where these claims
come from karna
was indeed a student of drona
drone acharya
right i mean how did karna become a
bosom friend of
of uh what's his name duryodhana how did
they meet
they met while being trained by this
great
uh guru dronacharya in the in the
various
martial arts so karna did receive
martial arts instruction from acharya i
don't know
what distortions have been made to the
story
i think there are certain indian serials
that depict this scenario differently
but if you read the actual text of the
mahabharat you will know that karna did
indeed receive instruction from the from
so there's no discrimination there there
was afterwards
later a con a
tournament an archery con contest
in which the kara was in pandavas
competed against each other or something
like that
and before each contestant was to start
his uh demonstration
of his of his prowess each contestant
was supposed to announce their
lineage so the pandavas and the corals
were clearly royalty
they had royal lineages and karna did
not have that
so that's why before karna could
announce his lineage
duryodhan said that he is not a king but
duryodhana made him the king of anger i
think bengal
so that elevated karuna to the status of
king so obviously there was
a difference between the aristocracy the
royalty and common people that exist
everywhere in the world i don't call
that discrimination of any kind
unless you're a marxist i mean even in a
marxist society you have classes there's
no such thing as classless society
now what about ekklevia well dronacharya
was
the teacher of royalty
his vocation his his his job he was
employed
by the aristocracy by the royalty right
by the by the core of us
to teach the korvers i mean
i know that he was a great teacher he
was good at teaching martial arts
it doesn't mean he he was in a position
to accept any
random student who came up to him and
said i want to i want you to be my guru
it doesn't work like that he was not the
only guru in bharat varsha
there were thousands of such gurus but
ekklavia wanted
to be his shishya and
dronachari had to refuse it
right so i don't call this
discrimination
it's not a case of discrimination
so basically what happens is that these
ancient stories are twisted
they are distorted and they are
portrayed in various
negative ways by either the popular
media you know these various serials
cinema etc and even by various
historians
right so that's what's done and that's
why we come up with these notions
and these beliefs
saurabh asks is it true that women and
sudras were not allowed to read the
vedas because they were perceived as
unequal and came lowest in the caste and
social hierarchy
and there were also quotes written in
the vedas that they will be punished for
it or is it just fabricated fake story
okay so first of all
i have said i have stated this in the
past that the rig veda
that a significant percentage of the
verses of the rigveda were written by
women
so if women wrote a significant portion
of the rig veda
then how is it that they would not be
allowed to read the vedas
it doesn't make any sense so that is
completely complete nonsense and once
again
this notion that shudras or whatever
were not allowed to read the vedas and
there was this cast hierarchy and all
that nonsense
you know this cast i have not spoken
about cast yet because i need to do a
proper exposition on that but
this entire notion of cast these four
different
social groups this stratification it is
a colonial invention
india was home to the jati and verna
system which is a
very complex arrangement
it's not an arrangement it's something
that just grew organically out of indian
society
jaatis and vernas right there's
different occupations
and and different clans and groupings
and lineages
we've never had these four groupings
the manuscript does kind of allude to
to four categories of people based upon
their occupations and all that
but it was never rigid it was never set
in stone
there was always social mobility the
person the great man who wrote the
ramayana
was born in a certain social category
and by the time he was done with his
work he was at the highest social
category of
as the author of one of the great texts
of india
i think he was a robber or something
angulimal
and he became valmiki the great
saint the great sage so that shows
that through your actions you could rise
to any status
and again this claim that certain
social strata were not allowed to read
the vedas
well that is debunked by the works of
the great uh
of dharam so darampal compiled
an extensive set of statistics from the
19th century during the british
occupation of india
he compiled statistics about the ancient
indian
pre macaulay and indigenous education
system
and what he found is is it may it's as
clear as day
boys and girls got were equal were equal
when it comes to education they both
got the same education and again boys
and girls of
every single class or so called caste of
society
were all they all got the same education
in india's ancient education system
so all these claims that are made by
western historians and marxist
historians
these are aimed at dividing and
fragmenting in
indian society and making indians
ashamed of who they are
these are lies these are fabrications do
not believe them
believe data believe facts facts are
available
but they are not but they are hidden
away you know they are not made widely
widely available you need to
know where to go and look and look at
them that's the problem
the truth is hidden away even though it
is available but it's hidden away in
various deep recesses of the world and
the lies are spread everywhere
through our education system that's the
problem
right what happened to dwarka how did it
end up under the sea
is the city still intact under the sea
so the western region of india the
region of savarashtra and kacha
is seismically very active we know that
there are earthquakes there on a regular
basis
and pretty strong earthquakes so in the
late
19th century you had this terrible
earthquake in kutch
i'm not sure what where it was on the
richtest scale but it was quite
catastrophic and in the early 21st
century i think in 2001 or two or
something
there was another devastating earthquake
in kutch which essentially destroyed
the old city of bhuj now you have a new
city of bhuj which is the
de facto capital of the region of kacha
so this region has always been prone to
strong
earthquakes sometimes devastating
earthquakes it is a consequence of the
slamming of the indian tectonic plate in
the indian land mass
into eurasia which gave rise to the
himalayas the greatest ma
the tallest mountains on the earth and
this region is always going to be
seismically active you're always going
to have earthquakes like the nepal
earthquake
the uttarakhand earthquake the various
kuch earthquakes
the earthquakes that you have in the
northeast region of india etc and the
andaman earthquake as well
so this so because of this
i think that so what is recorded in the
mahabharata is that arjuna was in dwarka
when this incident happened
there was a terrible earthquake and the
entire city of dwarkas
was slid under the ocean and was
swallowed up by the sea
so it's clearly uh this clearly
describes a very violent seismic event
uh it is known that the land shifts
during
violent earthquakes you sometimes have
the
rising up of islands in the middle of
the ocean out of nowhere sometimes
entire islands disappear
so this city was a coastal city
and it clearly went under the sea
because of a strong earthquake
and then the people who survived
recreated a new city new dwarka
where near where the old dwarka was once
was
and today if you just go into the sea
off the coast of new dwarka you will
find that
there is this ancient city still sunken
down there
so it is a fact that's how it ended up
ended up under the sea
is the city still intact into the sea
it's not intact it's very old carbon
dating only one
piece of wood has been carbon dated it
was dated to around 8000 bce
which is about 10 000 years before today
so that would place the mahabharata at a
very old
i mean around 10 000 years ago or 8 000.
i'm not sure exactly how old it is
it's about eight or ten thousand years
old that particular piece of wood that
was carbon dated
so i think we need to do more
investigations to
ascertain the time at which the
approximate time period in which this
event happened but the city is very old
it is
it's been under the ocean for thousands
of years so obviously the
quality of the artifacts and all that
must have degraded and today you have
all the dredging that's happening in the
harbor dwarka so these activities are
actually destroying what is left of
ancient dwarka and this is being done i
mean i i'm not
i don't understand how these activities
are allowed in such an
important archaeological site so the
city is not intact
it is under great threat today
rahul asks is that is it true that helen
and chandragupta were lovers and that
they wrote
letters to each other that caused
marriage and indo-greek collaboration
here's what happened chandragupta maurya
was the first
he was the founder of the mauryan
dynasty the morid empire
uh his mentor was the great vishnu gupta
chanakya
in the beginning of chandragupta's reign
as emperor of india
you had this greek uh invader called
seleucus niketa
who tried to invade western india
he was one of the generals of alexander
so
seleucus tried to invade western india
and there was conflict between the
mauryan empire and seleucus niketa
the invasion wasn't successful in any
way
but the two sides made came to an
agreement
they made an alliance and the alliance
was sealed by
uh by chandragupta accepting seleucus
nikera's daughter as his wife
so basically this made seleucus niketa
chandragupta's father in law
and therefore there was no possibility
of conflict once you are
once your family and
and chandragupta gave 500 war elephants
to his father-in-law as a gift
and seleucus used that to consolidate
his empire
in western asia and central asia and all
that so salukis was
i think he was one of the greatest greek
conquerors you know salukis nicked her
chandragupta's father-in-law so
chandragupta did have
a greek wife the daughter of seleucus i
don't know what her name was
okay so this was a political alliance it
was a political marriage
that's that's how things were done oh
always you know
political marriages so yes
one of his wives he had several wives as
the emperor of india
one of his wife wives was the daughter
of seleucus nikita
i am not sure if the if this lady was
the mother of bindu sir who succeeded
chandragupta who was
chandragupta's son and the second
emperor of the mauryan empire
but yes one of his wives was greek we
don't know what her name was i think
there are some indian
tv serials who have portrayed a greek
lady called helen
as chandragupta's lover or girlfriend or
whatever who becomes a wife
that's all fiction the truth is the
facts that we have at our disposal
are what i just outlined we don't know
what her name was
okay hussain asks please shed some light
on
native indian wars against the east
india company and british
i see a list of battles mentioned in
wikipedia
there's a link there however these
battles are generally ignored
and not discussed and what's not
discussed is how
indians tried to fight invaders just
like the native americans fought
yeah good question i've opened this link
here let me let me share it
just give me a minute let me share that
i will share the link that you have
mentioned
here we are okay so this is
tribal revolts in india before indian
independence a
list of such revolts in the 18th century
the 19th century which you have many
more in the 20th century
before independence so yes there is a
great deal of
of push back against the british
occupation of india by various people
who are
described as tribals in this particular
article so yes we did have that now
let's understand what really happened
so what happened is that you had a
number of tribal revolts
and these were basically by people who
dwelled who lived in the various
forests so india was was replete with
forests uh
those days okay the forest cover in
india is about 10 12
of the entire land area i think during
the 19th 18th and 19th centuries
it was much more so what happened is
that the british had
created these so-called forest
protection acts
okay the colonial british government of
india
so basically this converted about a
quarter
or a fifth of india's land mass into
so-called protected forests which were
actually prime hunting ground for the
british
so the british always had this tradition
of protected forests
in england from the time of william the
conqueror and his descendants etc
you had this protected forests in
england
which were which only had one purpose to
serve as hunting grounds for the royalty
so no commoner was allowed to
be to come into that forest to trespass
into the forest
and if any commoner would do that and
would actually kill a deer or something
that person would be hanged so these
forests
these protected forests like the new
forest in which
william rufus died by accident
apparently
that's another story so these forests
were basically nothing but
hunting grounds for the royalty so once
the british occupied india they
did the same thing here in india and
they called it
the forest protection act but it was
basically just to turn
a quarter of india's land mass into
hunting grounds prime hunting grounds
for
not the royalty but for the british
officers
etc of the east india company so the
forests
basically almost all the forests in
india were made
into government property exclusive
hunting rights were given to the british
officers
in india's puppet kings so-called
princely rulers
they acted as agents of the british so
whatever
forest land would fall under the domain
the the nominal domain of of a princely
ruler was basically
they would act as conservators and
agents of the british in that right
so what happened was that this british
overlords of india would
would hunt in these exclusive forest
lands
and in the at the same time the native
tribes people etc who lived there for
thousands of years
they were denied any kind of subsistence
activities there
no hunting no cutting of trees just for
basic subsistence activities they were
denied that
so they were denied the livelihood and
the lifestyle they had carried on for
thousands of years by the british and
this is one of the prime reasons why all
these tribes people
in inter interior parts of india and the
various forested parts of india
they rose up repeatedly in rewards
against the british
and these were crushed mercilessly i
mean
god knows what all what sort of
atrocities were done by the british
during this time
nothing is recorded our historians don't
care so these are
the reasons why these things happened
now you have
uh things like the anglo manipuri war
listed over here
i mean the manipuris are not tribals but
even that is listed here
so i mean there's a lot that happened
during this time there's a lot of push
back there was a lot of
uh resistance armed resistance of the
british
during this time
okay one second they
yes so see yeah so that's the answer to
this question in very brief
it's a very very big topic obviously
okay this is by sharad sir don't you
feel now that
treachery is so inherent in our people
uh every person from the ruling class
from clerks to is everyone tries to
trample upon others
no sense of community and my people
anymore
i wish there was another great ruler who
unites us but
they don't end up creating a rules-based
meritocratic society
breaks my heart but i'm at a loss
for new thoughts for india to revive us
okay so what okay so that's a great deal
to unpack but i will just deal with one
thing one
the main premise here is that treachery
is so
inherent in our people so this is a an
idea
or a belief that is i think ingrained
in us that treachery is
very common in india it is very
inherent to the indian people india
produces traitors
in great quantities i have heard people
from all walks of life
life say this i've heard military
generals say this
right people who served in the indian
armed forces they also believe
that indians have this tendency to be
traitors
so this is not true and let me
let me share some interesting
information
with you
okay so let's take a look at this
1980 this is the fbi website okay the
fbi united states
1985 was the year of the spy the cold
war was in its last gasps but you would
never have guessed
it by all the moles in the u.s
government who were passing secrets to
the soviet union
so you had all these different spies
john anthony walker jr
you he was a u.s navy warrant officer
who worked for the soviet union who
passed secrets top cryptographic secrets
to the soviets for more than 17 years
compromising at least one million
classified messages
he recruited three other people with
security clearances into his espionage
ring his brother his son and his friend
etc
you had jonathan jay pollard who was in
the intelligence in the navy's
anti-terrorist center
you had sharon marie's karnage cia clerk
stationed in ghana uh
larry wu chin who worked for china
and so many other people this is just
one
year it was called the year of the spy
but it
the 1980s were actually the decade of
the spy
the united states has just had
discovered during the
during the cold war hundreds of
americans
employed by the us government employed
in very sensitive jobs
who were passing secrets to the soviet
union and the same goes for the
for the uk kim philby is one of the most
famous
spies uh of the uk who defected to the
ussr
right so this goes on to show
that this treachery
is is something that that
that is part of every society a certain
percentage
of the population of any society is
going to have
anti-social criminal or treacherous
tendencies it's just a statistical fact
my friends
but we tend to somehow our historians
and our leaders
somehow tend to focus on the negatives
all the time
and we don't focus on the great heroes
we have produced of course
every nation is going to have some
traitors
i just showed you some examples in the
west the west has i think
the the percentage of traders was much
more in the west
and when you have a society that is
under foreign occupation
they're going to ensure that they find
the traitors and use them
for their benefit so so that's all it is
it's not like treachery is inherent to
our people absolutely not i disagree
with that
i think the people of india
traditionally have had
great ethics and morals because of our
culture and civilization
today of course things have changed but
i disagree that treachery is inherent in
our people
so i am very positive about india and
our people and our
culture and civilization
okay rishabh asks please tell us about
the origin
of the kushan empire and the gurjar
pratihar empire and the relationship
between them
so the origin of these two empires
that's very interesting
these are two very different uh
dynasties
empires the kushans are basically
the questions originated in the
so-called present-day xinjiang region
which is currently occupied illegally by
china
okay so that was the uh as far as we
know the homeland
of the kushan uh people the
river basin north of ladakh
north of the himalayas right so the
kushans
were uh an indo-european people by
ethnicity and by language if you look at
their genetics which is
available in abundance their genetic
lineages the most of them had the r1a1a
lineage which is identical
to what most indian males carry today
so essentially they were one of these
mlecha
clans that had migrated out of india
north of the himalayas several thousand
years ago
and they set up their kingdom over there
for a very long time
and eventually about two thousand years
ago they re-invaded india
right so it was not a foreign invasion
of india it was an invasion of india by
a group or a clan or a people who had
long ago migrated out of india
they were basically coming full circle
and this is evidenced by the fact that
there is
not one single record of any ethnic
or cultural or religious conflict
between the kushans and the
indian population they simply
assimilated harmoniously into into
indian society
which tells you that they were
culturally linguistically et cetera
ethnically
very much the same as indians right
so what is the origin of the quran the
first
kushan emperor or king that we know of
is kudula kasa who
lived in the first century about about
2000 years before today
he was the great grandfather of the
great emperor kanishka
who is believed to have lived in the
second century
i think his his coronation is believed
to be around
127 ce or thereabouts
the kanisha the great one of india's
greatest emperors he was he was a kuchan
and the kushan empire lasted about three
three and a half centuries it came to an
end approximately in the middle of the
fourth century
right and its successor state was the
great gupta empire
which had no relationship with the
kushans or maybe it did but we don't
know
if there was any significant
relationship right so the
questions basically their empire came to
an end and the kushan people
just quietly assimilated into indian
society in northern and western india
so i would say that the majority of
people in northern western central india
would have some kushan ancestry but it
doesn't mean that they are not indian
because the questions were the
descendants of indians anyway
so that is about the origins of the
kushans what about the pratiharas
the pratiharas came into became
the origin of the pratihara empire is in
the late
7th century their first king
the founder of the empire was a king
called
nagabutta now this guy naga bhatta
he was a feudatory he was a vasal of the
old
chavda dynasty in rajasthan so there
were
two branches of the ancient chakra
dynasty one was
centered in bin mal in rajasthan and the
other one was in gujarat
so the northern branch in bin mal was in
power between the 6th
and the 8th centuries and one of their
vassals was this
king called nagabutta after the northern
branch of the chaudhar dynasty declined
and fell out of power nagabutta became a
king in his own right
and he was a king in the 8th century
right so and the great so that is the
origin of the pratihara dynasty the
pratyahara empire
and their great greatest king was mihir
bhoj i think
who lived in the 9th century and the
this dynasty also came to an end in the
11th century when
mahmoud ghazni sucked and
conquered kanoj the guy who was
repeatedly uh pardoned by indians who
defeated him
that guy so it's a lesson of history we
should never have pardoned and let that
guy go
and escape with his life anyhow so i
hope that gives you an
idea of the origins of the koshan empire
and the gorjar pratihar
empire
rishikesh asks as per historical view
what's the difference between
rajputs and chatria is it right that
modern rajputs are descendants of white
hounds skittions or shakkas if not
where are these communities gone okay so
first of all there is no difference
between rajputs and chatrias
i mean rajputs are chatris
the chatria part of indian society is
traditionally the people who have
been warriors as their primary
occupation and the rajputs
were that so the question of the origin
of the rajputs is
is very much open today because there's
no research being done about this
see the indian historians hate the
rajputs
because because they represent the best
of indian society they were very brave
they were glorious they were valorous
and they defended india for centuries
i mean look at what happened in persia
the
demographics and religion of persia
changed completely
within a couple of decades after the
arabic invasion of persia
just within 20-30 years the entirety of
persia was completely transformed it had
become
an islamic country as we know very well
now when these
turkic arabic etc invasions of india
happened
india resisted for centuries and
the spearhead of the indian resistance
the great the great shield of india
where the rajputs
the rajputs defended india for centuries
they were unmatched in their bravery and
and valor
and also to some extent in their
stupidity because they allowed people
like mahmoud
mahmoud of ghazni to get away with his
life twice at least
but the rajputs despite their failings
despite their lack of unity etc
they defended india stoutly they shed
more blood than any other people
in defense of the motherland and that's
why the indian marxist historians hate
the rajput and that's why their
accomplishments are always
denigrated or or you know not spoken
about
and that's why there's no research been
done into the origin of the rajputs
so there are three different
schools of thought one is that they are
descendants of the white hounds the
shweta hunas
the second is that they're descendants
of uh
of uh these scythians the skittish the
indus keithians who were again
descendants of ancient indians there
were lectures and there is a third
school of thought
which says that the rajputs are
indo-iranians indo-sassanians
so we don't we don't really know what it
is so for example
let's take the chowder dynasty for
example because that's something i've
researched because of my own personal
interest
so this is an ancient rajput lineage so
there are
so there is one so the oldest records of
this dynasty
uh come from ancient indian uh
records the prabhupada the prabhupada
money etc
and the british have recorded this in
engl in english
so according to one version of the
british history of the chavdas
the chavdas were the descendants of the
great king napana who was a chhatrapa
who was a skithyan an indos-kethane king
he was a very
great king he was he he is mentioned in
the
greek account called the periplus of the
eritrean sea so he was a very
great ruler but he is not spoken about i
mean no one in india knows about him
today
so according to one version of the
british history of the chavdas the chav
does the resonance of the
of of this king according to another
version
which you will find in the numismatic
museum in mumbai
it says that the chavdas are
indo-sassanians which means that they
are indo-iranians
now again the iranians are essentially
part of the same ethnic group as the
indians
although most of us don't know that so
that is a
another theory and
there's another another thing as well
another data point the oldest
one of the oldest references to the
chava dynasty is the sri chapa
dynasty which is the old name of the
travelers so
the oldest recorded king of the sri
chapa dynasty
was a king called vyagramukha in bin
namal in rajasthan
and this guy the oldest recorded the
first recorded charda
was a first generation immigrant to
india he was a shweta huna
so he was a white hound so if this is
the truth about the origin
then this rajput lineage is of whitehun
origin otherwise it is of sketching
origin
or the third possibility is that it is
of indo-iranian origin
so this is the kind of confusion we have
today about the rajputs we have no idea
what the truth is
maybe it's a mixture of everything but
it doesn't really matter as because we
are all indians and even these
sasanians were of the same ethnicity as
us even the skittions were the same
ethnicity as us
and we don't really know who the white
horns were
but they were clearly not mongols or
turks so
it's all up in the air right now we
don't really know what the origins are
but it's a fascinating
topic of research
okay nishant asks why is it that the
mughals succeeded in ruling india for
such a long period of time
despite india having a long legacy of
great kings
and warriors like the rajputs and the
marathas were they militarily advanced
or did we lack unity or is it something
else
it's very simple you can be the bravest
people in the world but if you lack
unity
you can be defeated by an invading force
so these uh mughals
they ruled india for about three
centuries i think humayun came to power
in india
around 1526 or or something like that
i don't remember all the dates i don't
have to memorize them because you can
always look them up
i think it was 1526 if i'm not mistaken
and aurangzeb died in the 18th century
and the final end of the mughal empire
is said to be in 1857.
so that's uh about 300 years
approximately
yeah so it was not a very long period of
time but the reason these
turks whether it is the mamluks the
delhi sultanate or the mughals
the reason they were able to rule india
invade india successfully conquer india
parts of india not the entirety of india
the reason they could do this was
because
india was at the time not politically
united it was a fragmented nation
a fragmented civilization you had lots
of little kings small kings
all fighting each other there was a lack
of unity so these rajputs like you said
they were very brave etc but they
were not united that is what led to the
eventual long-term downfall of india
right and this is something you see
everywhere i mean i have made a video
about shingiskan i have studied
mongolia extensively so mongolia was
fragmented as a nation as a culture as a
people
for centuries and that is what the
chinese exploited repeatedly for
centuries
and it took one great man to unite the
entire nation ching is khan
and he had to struggle for several
decades
it it is only in his late 40s that he
was finally able to unify
every single warring clan of his people
under his rule and it is then that he
started his conquest of half the world
so unless you are united you will always
be
under the thumb of a foreign power like
the mongols were under china
and like we were under the turks so it
is all about a lack of unity the mongols
had always been great warriors but
because of their lack of unity the
chinese could manipulate them
any way they wanted indians
where also we always have had this
martial tradition this great warrior
tradition from the time of the
mahabharat in the ramayana
so despite having this great tradition
because of this lack of unity that we
had at the time that is why these
foreigners were able to rule us
okay kandarp asks according to
prithviraj russo written by
chandra bardai prithviraj johan defeated
muhammad ghori 17 times and let him go
every time
but the 18th time muhammad gory captured
him etc
however i say that there is only two
battles there were only two battles of
terrain
and prithwiraj was defeated in the
second battle which one should be
considered true
so okay you are right according to this
poem prithviraj rasa
written by chandra bardai it is said in
this in this account that prithviraj
defeated muhammad gory 17 times and let
him go over 17 times
so you see my friends i do not think
that prison was that
monumentally stupid okay
i don't think he was that stupid i know
that i have criticized him
for letting mohammed gori get go away
with his get away with his life in the
first battle of the rhine
if despite defeating him i don't think
he would have done that twice
let alone 17 times the second time
if prison won i think he would have
killed muhammad gauri
but unfortunately he had let him go the
first time and the second time he was
defeated
so the truth is that there were only two
battles 17 is nonsense
i mean this guy chand bardai he composed
this poem in order to glorify
prithwira johan despite his defeat but i
think he is
he's basically done the opposite of that
he's tried to portrait peter chohan as a
very stupid person
letting somebody go over 17 times i
think nobody is that stupid
in the world and please raj was not that
stupid a person he was a great king
he was a very brave man he was just
ah misguided i would say he he had the
wrong notions
of chivalry and nobility chivalry and
nobility is to be reserved for
your people not for the opponent not for
the enemy not for somebody who
who wishes you destroyed and and
enslaved
so the correct version is that there
were two battles of terrain
the first one we won the second one we
lost
and we know what happened after that
okay pritham asks some western people
are trying to inherit yoga as a part of
christianity
and most of the leftists show yoga as
not a part of hinduism
what are its consequences we need to
preserve our roots
and slam these these people
yes so in the west the west is now
appropriating yoga they are coming up
with new forms of yoga
hot yoga and cold yoga and drunk yoga
and beer yoga and goat yoga
and what not and we have allowed this to
happen
and now people are saying it is part of
christianity this christian yoga as well
and many people claim that yoga is
nothing but a set of exercises
that the british had introduced into
india
the truth is that you have
statutes of people in yogic
asanas during that that date back to the
harappan times
so it's clear that yoga is something
that was
uh that emerged in india it is very much
part of hinduism it is part of the yoga
school of thought
of indian of hindu philosophy okay so
which is which owes its birth to the
great
hindu sage patanjali so yoga is very
much a part of india but we have let it
slip away from us
what can be done about this it's very
simple just like
in kung fu there's only one institute
that sets the standards
which is the shaolin temple similarly
in india we need to create
a world yoga standards institute
that's all we need to do and this
institute must declare that
the standards of yoga will be decided by
this institute only and nobody else
so it will be the final authority of
deciding what is yoga and what is nude
yoga
that's all india needs to do to reclaim
this
and prevent this theft of our culture
and tradition
so my question is why is the government
of india
not doing this is it so hard to do
does it take lot of money to do this
do we not have a lot of money in india
i just don't understand really very
disappointing
ishwar asks india has a rich cultural
history which can be seen through our
monuments and
engineering marvels yet india has only
38 unesco
world heritage sites compared to that
with italy 55 france 41 uk 32
china many more in spite of their
smaller geographical extent in history
in india
what's the reason for this what are the
criteria for for selecting
places as unesco world heritage sites
excellent question my friend
yeah these little countries these tiny
pieces of geography they have more
unesco world heritage sites in india
and if you look at the list of
world heritage sites in india you will
see that a significant percentage of
these
so called world heritage sites are
colonial
sites either turkic uh monuments
like humayun's tomb or the what's what's
it called the
what's the tower there's a tower right
in delhi
i forgot the name whatever the tower is
yes
and then you have these churches and
convents in goa
which are built on top of destroyed
hindu temples
and so much more you have the so-called
the
the victoria terminus station in mumbai
which is now called shivaji
chatrapati shivaji terminus now it is a
british
it is a british building the british
constructed it with our money
and then you have the art deco buildings
in south mumbai which are a world
heritage site
in what way do these sites represent
india's heritage
i just don't understand the criteria
that we employ
to nominate site to nominate structures
and sites as unesco worldwide sites
and the second question i would like to
raise is that why do we need
the unesco stamp on our heritage why do
we need that
why can't we create our own list of
national heritage sites that have
nothing to do with the unesco
we can decide on our own instead of
every year petitioning
the uh the unesco to accept our
humble demand or our humble request
to make this site a unesco validated
said why do we need that
why can't we have our own standards why
can't we have our own list
of indian national heritage
sites why do we need the u.n stamp of
approval
i simply do not understand the
slave-mindedness
that permeates our governance system i
simply don't understand it
when will we decolonize our minds
really it's it's frustrating
okay one more question nimitz asks
nimitz says you say that our
constitution is made up of sections from
western constitutions
what would an what would an original
indian constitution
look like so you see namit i don't say
it you
own all you have to do is take a look at
the indian constitution
and show me which part is indian
so there is this uh us supreme court
judge
who who has written written this he has
written that
a constitution is the conscience of the
nation
it is the morality of the nation
so what a constitution is essentially
it's the it's the moral foundations
of the legal system and everything else
in a country
it's the ethical foundation of
everything that is in the country all
the institutions the laws everything
so that's what a consideration is
now our constitution says that india is
a secular socialist
republic is secularism something that
comes out of indian
values and morality and ethics is
secularism something that was part of
india's civilization
it is not is socialism
something that emerged out of india's
ancient history
it's not is the indian penal code
okay it's not the constitution etc but
if you look at all the sections of the
constitution
etc show me one thing that comes out of
india's
jurisprudence india's uh
india's foundational texts like the
vedas or anything anything
does it recognize the fact that india is
the world's oldest civilization
it does not so there is absolutely
nothing indian about india's
constitution
it is something that has been imposed
upon us
it is a foreign morality
it is a foreign conscious conscience
that has been imposed upon the nation
india already had a conscience a
morality a set of moral
principles a set of ethical principles
now we are told that this foreign
set of principles has to be adopted
and it is being it has been adopted in
india so it is basically a colonial
imposition upon us
what would an indian constitution look
like it would be based
on indian values indian cultural
and civilizational values if you look at
the mahajanapadas
and ancient indian governance systems
the king was elected by the people
right firstly and secondly the king had
a very simple duty
he his job his duty was to serve the
people serve the
the state of the country and to serve
dharma
these were the simple duties of the king
and that was the moral morality that the
king
was expected to follow
so an indian constitution has to be
based on those principles
as simple as that it has to be based on
dharma
not on secularism or or any other
nonsensical thing
import from the west so that's what an
indian constitution should do
should look like constitutions are
man-made things
constitutions are temporary as history
has shown throughout
so i think we need to reconsider this
constitution
there are many countries that have
thrown out the old constitution and
created new ones
sri lanka has done that france has done
that several times and many other
countries have done that
so if india is to decolonize some day
and become a self-respecting
country that others will also respect
someday then it needs to
to reject this fake constitution and
come up with its own
original dharmic constitution that's
what needs to happen
i hope that answers several questions
okay my friends i'm going to take up a
couple of live chat questions
and so let's let me take a look at what
you guys are talking about
nishte asks if not secular then what
would india be
dharmic it is the best
uh form of governance and and and of
it's the best set of moral and ethical
values
and it doesn't mean that it is
anti-minority or anything
right because in in dharma everybody is
considered to be the same everybody is
considered equal everybody gets the same
rights
so a dharmic constitution a dharmic set
of rules and laws
would be inherently superior to these
fake western moral
laws and all that so that's what india
should be
okay what else do we have
let me take up some other questions
tell us something about hussein brahmans
and imam hussain's army i'm afraid i
don't know anything about this i'm i'm
sorry i don't know anything about this
okay uh some more questions
are today's guptas the descendants of
the gupta empire we're not sure if
there's a one-to-one correspondence
between the gupta empire the gupta
dynasty
and the people of the gupta surname
today once again there is a lack of
information there's a lack of data
and therefore we cannot tell which the
current state of
historical research that we have today
whether there is a one-to-one
correspondence between the people who
have the surname today
and the ancient gupta empire so
it's something our historians need to
take up
harsh asks what was the extent of
knowledge of the world's geography the
ancient indians had during the ramayana
and mahabharata era
add as described in those texts
so i think during the vedic ages
the indians knew great deal about the
northern parts of asia
because uh they spoke in the there is
some
references to a place where you have
a night that lasts many days and daytime
that last many days
which seems to be the polar regions of
northern asia
so clearly the indians had had ventured
all the way north
according to if if those if these
texts are are giving us the correct
interpretation so it looks like indians
ventured
a great great deal north almost into the
polar regions
and during ashok's time it is it is
known that he was
aware of the of the king of egypt
ptolemy and various other kings to the
far to the west of india
so india did have a great deal of
knowledge of the world's geography
obviously we didn't know everything
because it was too far away
we did not have aircraft and satellites
those days
so obviously the entire geography of the
world may not have been known
possibly but clearly there was a great
deal of knowledge
the entire extent of the knowledge can
only be asserted once
once we analyze all these ancient texts
so that is something that needs to be
taken up
aditya asks do you believe that netaji
died in a plane crash
or survived and lived as gunnami baba
till 85
and was he present with lal bada shastra
in tashkent
i don't think he died in any plane crash
i think he survived i think
it is most likely that he he was the the
person who is called gumnami baba
so i think that that story is is more
credible than the plane crash theory
i don't think he was present with lal
bahadur shastri in tashkent
there is a photograph in which it seems
there seems to be a person
who looks somewhat like netaji subhash
in the bose
but there's another image in which the
same person looks different so
i don't think that theory is is very
credible
okay let me take one more question
before i end this session
okay akshith asks can india use
chanakya's
shastra for about political science and
economics the progress
absolutely yes those are timeless
principles
that are expounded upon and described in
great detail
in the arthashastra i think i have the
book somewhere here
so it tells you a lot about this kind of
the system of taxation that was
prevalent in those days the kind of
economics you had
the kind of geopolitics that was uh
that is that he prescribed a vishnu
prescribed
and the kind of state craft that he
prescribed and those are timeless
principles india can
can benefit a lot if india's present-day
leadership
were to follow those principles
india would benefit a lot from that
unfortunately we have forgotten about
chanakya and we are worshiping gandhi
so that is the great tragedy of india
today all right my friends
thank you very much uh i'm going to wrap
it up now
it's been 90 plus minutes thank you so
much for participating thank you for
your wonderful questions
and i will see you in the next episode
thank you very much
have a good night and before i before i
wrap it up
i would like to thank all of you who
have become members of this channel i
very very much appreciate it thank you
so much and
with that i bid you all a good day and a
good night and i will see you
in the next episode bye